Finding Aid for Gunnar Birkerts papers 1930-2002
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Project Files
  - Domino's Pizza, Inc. Headquarters, Ann Arbor, Michigan, 1984-1998
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Conceptual Sketches., Undated
        - [Sketches], untitled, Black and red ink sketches on six sheets of tracing paper, 10x12 to 16-1/2x18 inches (Map-case 6, Folder 1)
        - [Sketches], untitled, Blue and red ink sketches on four sheets of notebook paper and one sheet of spiral notebook paper, 8-1/2x11 inches (Map-case 6, Folder 1)
      - Schematic Design Drawings. Undated, except as noted
        - [Two Elevations], untitled, Colored pencil drawing on black-line print, 32x39-1/4 inches (Map-case 6, Folder 1)
        - [Entrance Elevation], untitled, Pencil drawing on brown paper with green and brown marker coloring, initialed, 21x36 inches, 9/6/87, and blue ink sketch by Thomas Monaghan, Chairman, in lower left corner (Map-case 6, Folder 1)
  - Domino's Pizza, Inc, Special Designs, Ann Arbor, Michigan, 1985-1986
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Conceptual Sketches., Undated
        - [Sketch of Chairman's Suite], untitled, Ink sketch on tracing paper with orange, blue and gray marker coloring, 12x24-1/2 inches (Map-case 6, Folder 2)
        - [Sketches of Chairman's Suite], untitled, Ink sketches on five sheets of tracing paper with marker coloring, 12x18-3/4 to 12x29-1/2 inches, and on one black-line print with notations, 12x21 inches (Map-case 6, Folder 2)
        - [Sketches of Stained Glass], untitled, Black marker sketches on nine sheets of tracing paper, 12x22 to 12x24-3/4 inches (Map-case 6, Folder 2)
        - [Layout of Stained Glass], untitled, Colored marker drawing and blue ink notations on black-line print, 14-3/4x29 inches (Map-case 6, Folder 2)
        - [Sketches of Light Pedestal], untitled, Black ink sketches on graph paper, 8-1/2x11 inches (Map-case 6, Folder 2)
        - [Sketches of Log Holder], untitled, Black marker sketches on three sheets of tracing paper, 12x20-1/2 to 12x23-3/4 inches, and blue ink sketches on one sheet of graph paper, 8-1/2x11 inches (Map-case 6, Folder 2)
      - Schematic Design Drawings., Undated
        - [Chairman's Suite Section], untitled, Red pencil drawing on black-line print, 19x34-1/2 inches (Map-case 6, Folder 2)
        - [Log Holder], untitled, Pencil drawing on tracing paper, 12x22 inches (Map-case 6, Folder 2)
  - Domino's Pizza, Inc, Prototype Franchise Building, Jackson, Michigan, 1986-1988
    - Project Files
      - Newspaper Articles, 1987-1989 (Box 9)
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Conceptual Sketches, Undated
        - [Sketch], untitled, Ink sketch with blue marker coloring on tracing paper, 18x19 inches (Map-case 6, Folder 3)
        - [Sketch], untitled, Ink sketch with blue and gray marker coloring on tracing paper, 18x19-1/2 inches (Map-case 6, Folder 3)
        - [Sketches], untitled, Ink sketches with marker coloring on seven sheets of tracing paper, 12x21 to 18x25-1/2 inches (Map-case 6, Folder 3)
  - Domino's Farms Tower, Ann Arbor, Michigan (unbuilt project), 1987-1988
    - Project Files
      - Original and Revised Proposals for Tower, 1/6/87; 01/09/1987; 01/15/1987 (Box 9)
      - Preliminary Design Cost Estimate and Revised Proposal for Tower, 02/05/1987; 02/19/1987 (Box 9)
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Conceptual Sketches. Undated, except as noted
        - [Sketch], untitled, Ink sketch on tracing paper, 18x17-1/2 inches (Map-case 6, Folder 4)
        - [Sketch], untitled, Blue ink sketch on tracing paper, 23x12 inches (Map-case 6, Folder 4)
        - [Sketches], untitled, Ink and colored pencil sketches on one sheet of vellum, 12x6 inches, two sheets of graph paper, 8-1/2x11 inches, and one electrostatic print, 8-1/2x11 inches (Map-case 6, Folder 4)
        - [Sketch of Roof], untitled, Blue ink sketch on tracing paper, 22x12 inches (Map-case 6, Folder 4)
        - [Sketch of Roof], untitled, Ink sketch with yellow marker coloring on tracing paper, 12x16-1/4 inches. (Map-case 6, Folder 4)
        - [Sketch of Roof], untitled, Ink sketch on tracing paper, 12x17 inches (Map-case 6, Folder 4)
        - [Roof Studies], untitled, undated, 02/08/1987; 06/05/1987; Blue, green and black ink sketches on thirteen sheets of tracing paper, 12x11 to 12x28 inches, two sheets of graph paper, 8-1/2x11 inches, and one sheet of white paper, 8-1/2x11 inches, one initialed and dated 2/8/87 and three initialed and dated 6/5/87 with notation "Columbus" (Map-case 6, Folder 4)
      - Conceptual Sketches
        - [Faade Studies], untitled, undated, 06/20/1988; 7/88; Colored ink sketches with marker coloring on twelve sheets of tracing paper, 18-1/4x12 to 35-1/2x18 inches, two initialed and dated 6/20/88 and one initialed and dated 7/88 (Map-case 6, Folder 5)
      - Conceptual Sketches., Undated
        - [Faade Study], untitled, Electrostatic print with pencil coloring, 24x18 inches (Map-case 6, Folder 6)
        - [Faade Study], untitled, Blue ink and purple pencil sketch on tracing paper, initialed, 33x18 inches (Map-case 6, Folder 6)
        - [Faade Studies], untitled, Black and brown ink sketches on ten sheets of tracing paper, 11-1/2x12 to 25x12 inches, and four electrostatic prints with marker coloring, 24x18 inches (Map-case 6, Folder 6)
        - [Sketch and Drawing of] Domino's Tower Conference Center, Black ink and red pencil drawing on vellum with gray and green marker coloring, initialed, 14-3/4x14 inches (Map-case 6, Folder 6)
      - Schematic Design Drawings. Undated, except as noted
        - West Elevation, undated; 01/15/1987; Pencil and green pencil drawing on two sheets of vellum, 21x22 & 21-3/4x21 (Map-case 6, Folder 7)
        - [Elevations], untitled, 06/11/1988; Colored ink and pencil drawings on two electrostatic prints, drawn on train between "Bern and Firenze," one initialed, 10-1/2x8 & 8-1/2x11 inches (Map-case 6, Folder 7)
        - [Elevation], untitled, 07/11/1988; Colored ink and pencil drawing on electrostatic print, drawn on train between "Basil and Firenze," initialed, 8-1/2x11 inches (Map-case 6, Folder 7)
        - [Elevation], untitled, Black and brown ink drawing on black-line print, 22-1/2x10-1/4 inches (Map-case 6, Folder 7)
        - [Elevation Perspective], untitled, Colored crayon drawing on blue-line print, 27-1/4x19-1/4 inches (Map-case 6, Folder 7)
        - [Elevation Perspective], untitled, Colored crayon drawing on blue-line print, initialed, 24x18 inches (Map-case 6, Folder 7)
        - [Roof Elevation], untitled, Colored pencil-on-vellum drawing, 14-1/4x21 inches 1/12/88 (Map-case 6, Folder 7)
        - [Roof Elevation], untitled, Red pencil and black ink drawing on electrostatic print with marker coloring, 17x11 inches (Map-case 6, Folder 7)
        - North Elevation, Ink drawing with orange and gray marker coloring on black-line print, 21x30 inches (Map-case 6, Folder 7)
        - [Section], untitled, Pencil and red pencil drawing on vellum graph paper, 8-1/2x11 inches
        - [Section], untitled, Yellow and brown marker coloring on two electrostatic prints, 11x17 inches (Map-case 6, Folder 7)
        - Cross-Section and Elevation, Ink drawing on tracing paper overlaid on black-line print, 27-1/2x42 inches (Map-case 6, Folder 7)
  - Minnesota Judicial Building Competition, St. Paul, Minnesota (unbuilt project), 1984-1985
    - Project Files
      - Design Submission, March 1985 (Box 9)
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Conceptual Sketches., Undated
        - [Sketches], untitled, Ink sketches on tracing paper, 12x21-1/4 inches (Map-case 6, Folder 8)
        - [Sketch], untitled, . Ink sketch on tracing paper, 18x25-1/4 inches (Map-case 6, Folder 8)
        - [Sketch], untitled, Ink sketch on tracing paper, 12x16-1/2 inches (Map-case 6, Folder 8)
        - [Sketch], untitled, Blue ink and red pencil sketch on tracing paper, 12x25 inches (Map-case 6, Folder 8)
        - [Sketch], untitled, Blue ink and red pencil sketch on tracing paper, 12x26 inches (Map-case 6, Folder 8)
        - [Elevation], untitled, Ink sketch on tracing paper, 12x13-1/2 inches (Map-case 6, Folder 8)
        - [Elevation], untitled, Ink sketches on tracing paper, 12x20 inches (Map-case 6, Folder 8)
      - Conceptual Sketches. Undated, except as noted
        - [Early Sketches],untitled, undated; 08/19/1985; Black, green and blue ink and purple crayon sketches on thirteen sheets of tracing paper, 12x12-1/2 to 18x32 inches (Map-case 6, Folder 9)
        - [Elevations], untitled, Ink sketches on four sheets of tracing paper, 12x18 to 12x28 inches (Map-case 6, Folder 9)
      - Schematic Design Drawings., Undated
        - [Site Plan],untitled, Colored pencil drawings on two blue-line prints, 16x30 & 17-3/4x30 inches (Map-case 6, Folder 9)
  - Minnesota History Center Competition, St. Paul, Minnesota (unbuilt project), 1984-1986
    - Project Files
      - Design Submission, June 1986 (Box 9)
      - Newspaper Articles, 1986 (Box 9)
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Conceptual Sketches.
        (Undated, except as noted)
        - [Early Sketch of Site Plan], untitled, Blue ink sketch on tracing paper, initialed, 12x28-1/2 inches (Map-case 7, Folder 1)
        - [Early Site Plan], untitled, Green ink sketch on tracing paper, 12x23 inches (Map-case 7, Folder 1)
        - [Site Plan Studies], untitled, undated; 04/21/1986; Blue and green ink and blue crayon sketches on twelve sheets of tracing paper, 12x17-1/4 to 18x34-3/4 inches, one initialed and dated 4/21/86 (Map-case 7, Folder 1)
        - [Sketch], untitled, Blue ink sketch on tracing paper, 12x18-1/2 inches (Map-case 7, Folder 1)
        - [Sketch], untitled, Blue ink sketch on tracing paper, 12x13 inches (Map-case 7, Folder 1)
        - [Sketch], untitled, Blue and green ink sketch with yellow and green marker coloring on tracing paper, 18x20-1/4 inches (Map-case 7, Folder 1)
        - [Sketch of Structure], untitled, Blue ink sketch on tracing paper with notations, initialed, 12x16 inches (Map-case 7, Folder 1)
        - [Sketches], untitled, Ink sketches on graph paper, 8-1/2x11 inches (Map-case 7, Folder 1)
        - [Sketches], untitled, Ink sketches on graph paper, 8-1/2x11 inches (Map-case 7, Folder 1)
        - [Sketch], untitled, 05/06/1986; Ink sketch on Architecture Magazine mailer, initialed, 8-3/4x11-3/4 inches (Map-case 7, Folder 1)
        - [Sketches], untitled, Black, brown and blue ink sketches on eleven sheets of tracing paper, 11x12 to 18x26-1/2 inches, and one sheet of steno pad paper, 6x9 inches (Map-case 7, Folder 1)
      - Conceptual Sketches., Undated
        - [Sketches], untitled, Pink marker sketches on two oversized sheets of tracing paper, 24x72 & 24x67 inches. Drawn on wall by Gunnar Birkerts while explaining concept to engineers (Map-case 7, Folder 2)
        - [Facade Study], untitled, Blue ink sketch on tracing paper, 12x21-1/2 inches (Map-case 7, Folder 2)
        - [Facade Study], untitled, Pencil and purple pencil drawing on vellum, 13-3/4x24 inches (Map-case 7, Folder 2)
        - [Facade Study and Section], untitled, Pencil and red pencil drawing on vellum, 17-1/4x23 inches (Map-case 7, Folder 2)
        - [Facade Studies], untitled, Blue and green ink sketches on five sheets of tracing paper, 12x15-1/4 to 12x20 inches (Map-case 7, Folder 2)
        - [Facade Studies], untitled, Pencil and colored pencil drawings on three sheets of vellum, 14x24 to 17-1/4x19 inches (Map-case 7, Folder 2)
        - [Entrance Canopy Studies], untitled, Black and blue ink sketches with yellow and gray marker coloring on twelve sheets of tracing paper, one initialed, 12x20 to 18x24-1/4 inches (Map-case 7, Folder 2)
      - Schematic Design Drawings., Undated
        - [Site Plan], untitled, Two pencil and colored pencil drawings on vellum, 23x36 inches (Map-case 7, Folder 2)
        - [Sections], untitled, Pencil and colored pencil drawing on vellum, 20-1/4x36 inches (Map-case 7, Folder 2)
  - Bardha Residence Birmingham, Michigan, 1984-1989
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Conceptual Sketches., Undated
        - [Sketch], untitled, Blue ink sketch on tracing paper, 16-1/4x18 inches (Map-case 7, Folder 3)
        - [Roof], untitled, Ink sketch on tracing paper, 12x24-1/2 inches (Map-case 7, Folder 3)
        - [Roof], untitled, Blue ink sketch on tracing paper with purple and green marker coloring, 18x34 inches (Map-case 7, Folder 3)
        - [Roof Studies], untitled, Blue and black ink and blue crayon sketches on seven sheets of tracing paper, 12x18-3/4 to 18x28 inches, and black ink sketches on four sheets of steno pad paper, 6x9 inches (Map-case 7, Folder 3)
      - Conceptual Sketches. Undated, except as noted
        - [Floor Plan and Elevation], untitled, Brown and blue ink sketches on fifteen sheets of tracing paper, one initialed, 12x15-3/4 to 18x22 inches (Map-case 7, Folder 4)
        - [Door Elevation], untitled, 04/08/1990; Ink sketch on tracing paper, initialed, 18-1/2x18 inches (Map-case 7, Folder 4)
      - Schematic Design Drawings, undated; Marker and pencil coloring on blue-line prints, except as noted
        - [Interior Section], untitled, Red pencil and ink drawing on tracing paper, 12x15 inches (Map-case 7, Folder 4)
        - East Elevation, 15x15-1/2 inches (Map-case 7, Folder 4)
        - East and South Elevations, 15x42 inches (Map-case 7, Folder 4)
        - [Floor Plan], untitled, 18x22-1/2 inches (Map-case 7, Folder 4)
  - University of Michigan Sports Services Building, Ann Arbor, Michigan, 1985-1990
    - Project Files
      - Newspaper Article, November 1990 (Box 9)
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Conceptual Sketches., Undated
        - [Early Roof Study], untitled, Blue ink sketch on tracing paper, 12x24-1/2 inches (Map-case 7, Folder 5)
        - [Early Roof Study], untitled, Black and blue ink sketches on two sheets of tracing paper with blue and orange marker coloring, 18x28 inches. Second sketch is digital image only
        - [Early Roof Studies], untitled, Blue and orange marker sketches on five sheets of tracing paper, one initialed, 12x16-1/2 to 12x28 inches (Map-case 7, Folder 5)
      - Schematic Design Drawings., Undated
        - Section "C", Ink and red pencil drawing on blue-line print with blue and orange marker coloring, 12-1/4x40-3/4 inches (Map-case 7, Folder 5)
  - Oberlin College Conservatory of Music Library Addition, Oberlin, Ohio, 1986-1988
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Conceptual Sketches., Undated
        - [Sketch], untitled, Ink sketch on tracing paper, 12x22 inches (Map-case 7, Folder 5)
        - [Sketch], untitled, Ink sketch on tracing paper with marker coloring, 12x26 inches (Map-case 7, Folder 5)
        - [Sketches], untitled, Ink sketches on graph paper, 8-1/2x11 inches (Map-case 7, Folder 5)
        - [Sketches], untitled, Ink sketches on graph paper with green marker coloring, 8-1/2x11 inches (Map-case 7, Folder 5)
  - Weinstein Residence, San Francisco, California (unbuilt project), 1986
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Conceptual Sketches
        - [Early Sketch], untitled, 03/02/1986; Blue ink sketch with marker coloring on tracing paper, 12x21-1/2 inches (Map-case 7, Folder 5)
        - [Sketch], untitled, 03/03/1986; Blue ink sketch with yellow marker coloring on tracing paper, 12x24-1/2 inches (Map-case 7, Folder 5)
        - [Sketch], untitled, 03/03/1986; Blue ink sketch with blue marker coloring on tracing paper, 12x19-1/2 inches (Map-case 7, Folder 5)
        - [Early Sketches], untitled, undated; 3/2/86-3/4/86; Blue ink sketches, some with marker coloring, on nine sheets of tracing paper, 12x17 to 12x24 inches (Map-case 7, Folder 5)
  - University of Wyoming Museum Competition, Laramie, Wyoming (unbuilt project), 1986
    - Project Files
      - Architect's Conceptual Statement and Design Presentation Notes, 08/28/1986 (Box 9)
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Conceptual Sketches. Undated, except as noted
        - [Site Plan], untitled, Ink sketch with green and yellow marker coloring on tracing paper, 12-1/4x22 inches (Map-case 7, Folder 6)
        - [Site Plan], untitled, 04/28/1986; Blue ink sketches on graph paper, initialed, 8-1/2x11 inches (Map-case 7, Folder 6)
        - [Site Plan], untitled, Black and blue ink sketches on six sheets of tracing paper with green and yellow marker coloring, 12-1/4x14-1/2 to 12-1/4x23 inches (Map-case 7, Folder 6)
        - [Sketch], untitled, Ink sketch with green and yellow marker coloring on tracing paper, 12-1/4x25 inches (Map-case 7, Folder 6)
        - [Sketch], untitled, Ink sketch with yellow marker coloring on tracing paper, 12-1/4x22 inches (Map-case 7, Folder 6)
        - [Sketch], untitled, Ink sketch with yellow marker coloring on graph paper, 8-1/2x11 inches (Map-case 7, Folder 6)
        - [Sketches], untitled, Blue, green, brown and black ink and blue crayon sketches on sixteen sheets of tracing paper, 12x15 to 24x35 inches, one blue ink sketch on graph paper, 8-1/2x11 inches, and one black ink sketch on steno pad paper, 6x9 inches (Map-case 7, Folder 6)
        - [Elevation Perspective], untitled, Blue ink sketches on seven sheets of tracing paper, 12x10-1/2 to 12x16-1/2 inches (Map-case 7, Folder 6)
      - Schematic Design Drawings., Undated
        - [Site Plan], untitled, Ink and red pencil sketch on black-line print with green and brown marker coloring, 21x30 inches, dated "Mon. July 7" (Map-case 7, Folder 6)
        - Composite Section, Looking West, Pencil and red pencil drawing on vellum, 12x35-3/4 inches (Map-case 7, Folder 6)
        - [Elevation], untitled, Black and blue ink sketch with gray and brown marker coloring on one sheet of tracing paper taped to black-line print, 12-3/4x36 inches (Map-case 7, Folder 6)
  - University of Michigan Library, Flint, Michigan, 1986-1995
    - Project Files
      - Architect's Conceptual Statement (Box 9)
      - Newspaper Articles, 1985 (Box 9)
    - Architectural Drawings
      - First Scheme Conceptual Sketches. Undated, except as noted
        - [Site Plan], untitled, 04/03/1986; 04/08/1986; Ink sketches on three electrostatic prints, initialed, 8-1/2x12 inches (Map-case 7, Folder 7)
        - [Sketches], untitled, 12/23/1986; Ink sketches on graph paper, initialed, 8-1/2x11 inches (Map-case 7, Folder 7)
        - [Sketches], untitled, 12/23/1986; Ink sketches on graph paper, initialed, 8-1/2x11 inches (Map-case 7, Folder 7)
        - [Sketch], untitled, 01/20/1987; Ink sketch on tracing paper, 12x27-1/4 inches (Map-case 7, Folder 7)
        - [Sketch], untitled, Ink sketch on tracing paper, 12x24 inches (Map-case 7, Folder 7)
        - [Sketch], untitled, 1/87; Ink sketch on reverse of letter by Karin Wylie, 8-1/2x11 inches (Map-case 7, Folder 7)
        - [Sketches], untitled, Black, blue and brown ink sketches on seven sheets of tracing paper, 12x17-1/2 to 18x30-1/2 inches (Map-case 7, Folder 7)
      - Final Scheme Conceptual Sketches. Undated, except as noted
        - [Site Plan], untitled, Blue ink sketch on tracing paper, 12x20 inches (Map-case 7, Folder 8)
        - [Site Plan], untitled, 01/17/1991; Blue ink sketch on tracing paper, initialed, 12x17 inches (Map-case 7, Folder 8)
        - Phases I, II and III [Site Plan], Ink sketch on electrostatic print with purple marker coloring, 8-1/2x11 inches (Map-case 7, Folder 8)
        - [Section], untitled, 08/04/1991; Blue and green ink sketch on tracing paper, initialed, 18x18 inches (Map-case 7, Folder 8)
        - [Sketch], untitled, Blue ink sketch on tracing paper, 18x23 inches (Map-case 7, Folder 8)
        - [Sketch], untitled, Blue and red ink sketch on tracing paper, 18x23-3/4 inches (Map-case 7, Folder 8)
        - [Sketch], untitled, Ink sketch on tracing paper with green marker coloring, 18x31 inches (Map-case 7, Folder 8)
        - [Sketch], untitled, Ink sketch on tracing paper, 18x27 inches (Map-case 7, Folder 8)
        - [Site Plan], untitled, Ink sketch on electrostatic print, 8-1/2x11 inches (Map-case 7, Folder 8)
        - [Sketches], untitled, undated 08/04/1991 and one dated, 08/10/1991, Black, blue, red, brown and green ink sketches on twelve sheets of tracing paper, five initialed, 12x13-1/2 to 18x32-1/4 inches (Map-case 7, Folder 8)
      - Final Scheme Schematic Design Drawings., Undated
        - [Elevation], untitled, Ink and pencil drawing on vellum with gray marker coloring, 11-3/4x42 inches (Map-case 7, Folder 8)
        - Library/Telecommunications Center Plan, Level 2, Pencil and red pencil drawing on blue-line print with yellow and gray marker coloring, 23-1/2x41-1/2 inches (Map-case 7, Folder 8)
  - University of California Central Library Addition, San Diego, California, 1987-1993
    - Project Files
      - Correspondence, 1990-1994 (Box 9)
      - Newspaper Articles, 1987-1988 (Box 9)
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Conceptual Sketches. Undated, except as noted
        - [Early Sketches], untitled, Ink sketches on tracing paper, 18x22-1/4 inches (Map-case 8, Folder 1)
        - [Early Sketches], untitled, Blue and black ink sketches on tracing paper, 12x29 inches (Map-case 8, Folder 1)
        - [Early Sketches], untitled, Green ink sketches on tracing paper, initialed, 18x28-1/2 inches (Map-case 8, Folder 1)
        - [Sketch], untitled, Blue ink sketch on tracing paper with green, orange and gray marker coloring, 12x32 inches. (Map-case 8, Folder 1)
        - [Sketches], untitled, Green, blue, brown and black ink sketches on five sheets of tracing paper, two initialed, 12x23-3/4 to 18x28 inches (Map-case 8, Folder 1)
        - [Section], untitled., 08/26/1987; Digital image only of black ink sketch on steno pad paper, 6x9 inches
      - Schematic Design Drawings. Undated, except as noted
        - [Plot Plan], untitled, 11/07/1987; Pencil and red pencil drawing on vellum, 21x28-1/4 inches, initialed (Map-case 8, Folder 1)
        - Central Library Cross-Section [Berm Design, First Proposal], Ink sketch on electrostatic print, 8-1/2x11 inches (Map-case 8, Folder 1)
        - Presentation Drawing of Exploded Axonometric, Two photographic prints of drawings with colored pantone, 19x24 inches (Map-case 8, Folder 1)
  - Papal Altar and Furniture, Pontiac Silverdome, Pontiac, Michigan, 1987
    - Project Files
      - Newspaper Articles, 1987 (Box 9)
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Conceptual Sketches. Undated, except as noted
        - [Early Site Plan], Pencil, orange pencil and ink sketch on tracing paper, initialed, 18x28-1/2 inches (Map-case 8, Folder 2)
        - [Early Sketches of Throne], untitled., 04/12/1987; Brown ink sketches on tracing paper, 12x23-1/2 inches (Map-case 8, Folder 2)
        - [Early Sketches of Throne], untitled, 04/12/1987; Brown ink sketches on tracing paper, 12x18-3/4 inches (Map-case 8, Folder 2)
        - [Early Sketch of Throne], untitled, 04/12/1987; Brown ink sketch on tracing paper, 12x19-1/4 inches (Map-case 8, Folder 2)
        - [Sketch], untitled, Blue ink sketch on tracing paper with yellow marker coloring, 12x18-1/2 inches (Map-case 8, Folder 2)
        - [Sketches of Throne], untitled, . Black and blue ink sketches on tracing paper with yellow marker coloring, 18x29-3/4 inches (Map-case 8, Folder 2)
        - [Sketches of Throne and Cardinal's Chairs], untitled, Black and blue ink sketches on thirteen sheets of tracing paper, 12x8-1/2 to 18x26-3/4 inches (Map-case 8, Folder 2)
      - Schematic Design Drawings
        - [Throne Elevation and Section], untitled, 04/18/1987; Pencil and red pencil drawing on vellum, initialed, 24x36 inches (Map-case 8, Folder 2)
        - [Throne Elevation and Section], untitled, 04/24/1987; Pencil and red and purple pencil drawing on vellum, 21x24 inches (Map-case 8, Folder 2)
        - [Sections of] Acolyte's Bench, 06/29/1987; Pencil-on-vellum drawing with brown pencil coloring, initialed, 12x14 inches (Map-case 8, Folder 2)